Guide to the Riggs Family papers, 1672-2006 MS2239
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Paper documents, circa 1785 - 2006; Series 3; 3 Linear Feet
  - Publications and research, 1939-1956; Series 3 Subseries 3; 1.5 Linear Feet 2 document boxes 2 slim document boxes
    - Edited copy of Riggs book by John Beverley Riggs [1 of 3], circa 1939; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Edited copy of Riggs book by John Beverley Riggs [2 of 3], circa 1939; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Edited copy of Riggs book by John Beverley Riggs [3 of 3], circa 1939; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Picture of visit of Prince of Wales to Mt. Vernon with President Buchanan, 1861; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Research - University of California Berkeley, 1959-1962; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Genealogy research - the Macgill-McGill family of Maryland book, 1948; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Genealogy research - Warfield, 1956-1958; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Report on books from Mansion at Longwood Gardens by John Beverley Riggs, 1985; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Research - Mystic, Connecticut - Stillman library, 1962; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Research - American Families Fishwick lecture, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Notes on Hillwood, 1965 April; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Riggs family and Georgetown University, 1983 September 27; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - The Riggs family book papers by John Beverley Riggs, 1938-1939; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Genealogy research by John Beverley Riggs, 1906-1962; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Marrioth - Riggs - Grifith - Sheppard's Forrest deeds, 1684-1762; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - John Beverley Riggs' notes on Polk family, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Genealogy research - puritans in Virginia and Maryland, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Research - Geofroy vs. Riggs U.S. Supreme Court, 1889; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Henry L. Stimson and the Philippines by John Beverley Riggs, 1950 January; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Colonel Stimson and the Philippines by John Beverley Riggs, 1950 May; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Third report on the Henry L. Stimson collection by John Beverley Riggs, 1950 October 12; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Papers of J. Franklin Jameson Report and Inventory by John Beverley Riggs, 1956 January; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Okinawa Air Depot Dispatch - John Beverley Riggs, 1945-1946; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Research - Riggs material, 1953 March 25; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Genealogy research - Riggs and Ridgely family, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Book - Para La Historia De La Florida, 1963 March 4; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      The book is in Spanish and was published in 1857.
    - Trumbull Stickney - fourth copy by Thomas Riggs, Jr. [1 of 2], 1949 May; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Trumbull Stickney - fourth copy by Thomas Riggs, Jr. [2 of 2], 1949 May; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Genealogy research notebook, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Negatives and copy of letter from Roger B. Taney [Baltimore/Washington], 1861; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      This letter is a copy from the Library of Congress.
    - Article regarding Richard C. Riggs, 1945 January 29; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Research - Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery, 1946-1947; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Genealogy research - Wills and their Whereabouts, 1951; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Research - newsclippings of interest John Beverley Riggs, 2003-2004; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Sheet music, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Diaries, 1878-1913; Series 3 Subseries 4; 0.75 Linear Feet 1 document box 1 slim document box
    The diaries within this subseries belonged to Mrs. L. R. Coudert, Elizabeth Coudert, and Thomas Lawrason Riggs. There are multiple diaries written by Thomas Lawrason Riggs, one includes details of his time as a student at Yale University and Harvard University. He included various notes about spending time at the White House in Washington, DC. The materials date from 1878 – 1913.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Diary of Mrs. L. R. Coudert, 1878; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Diary of Elizabeth Coudert, 1903; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      Includes numerous newspaper clippings throughout diary.
    - Diary of Thomas Lawrason Riggs, 1903; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Diary of Thomas Lawrason Riggs, 1906; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Diary of Thomas Lawrason Riggs, 1909-1913; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      While a student at Yale and at Harvard Universities. Includes passages about Cole Porter (see insert). Also Helen Taft - later wife of President Taft, 1912 December 22. Also spending time at the White House, Washington, DC at various times.
  - Paper documents (original donation), 1835-1962; Series 3 Subseries 5
    Arranged either by format type or chronologically within a box.
    - Letter to Lawrason Riggs with transcription and translation, 1835-1962; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Documents from 1871 requesting American repayment of British loans to the Confederacy. Result of the Treaty of Washington, May 8 1871., Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Invitation Acceptances to dinner hosted by Mr. & Mrs. Riggs (George Washington Riggs Jr. and Janet Madeleine Cecilia Shedden?), 03\11\1871; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Obituraries for Mrs. G.W. Riggs (Janet Madeleine Cecilia Shedden Riggs)--newspaper clippings & photocopies, 1871; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Thomas Riggs, Governor of Alaska and family, newspaper clippings, circa 1903- circa 1957; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Handwritten correspondence between EFR and the Mount Vernon Ladies Association, 1909; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Thomas Riggs, Governor of Alaska, proclamation, 1918; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Thomas Riggs, Governor of Alaska, stocks and business correspondence, 1922-1947; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Letter to Thomas Riggs from Mary B. Chapman and photo of Thomas Riggs' parents, 1925; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Photocopies of Elisha Riggs Jr. letters and information on the George Peabody papers from the Essex Institute, 1987; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Manuscript: "Remarks on Some of the Oldest Maps in America" by Frederic Kunstmann, undated; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Unknown documents: leaves from books; copy of handwritten article in French, undated; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Typed/numbered manuscript: "The Riggs Family of Maryland" by John Beverley Riggs [1/4], 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Typed/numbered manuscript: "The Riggs Family of Maryland" by John Beverley Riggs [2/4], 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Typed/numbered manuscript: "The Riggs Family of Maryland" by John Beverley Riggs [3/4], 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Typed/numbered manuscript: "The Riggs Family of Maryland" by John Beverley Riggs [4/4], 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Corrigenda for "The Riggs Family of Maryland" manuscript, 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Financial information on the publication of "The Riggs Family of Maryland" by The Lord Baltimore Press, 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Printed manuscript of "The Riggs Family of Maryland" [1/2], 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Printed manuscript of "The Riggs Family of Maryland" [2/2], 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Riggs Family Coat of Arms - 6 copies, 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - "Riggs Family of Maryland" manuscript: 2 tables of contents, 3 versions of "list of pictures," 4 versions of index, 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - "Riggs Family of Maryland": 5 typed biographies, 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Three images for use in "The Riggs Family of Maryland", 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Long length manuscript "Riggs Genealogy" (title page-p.85) [1/2], 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Long length manuscript "Riggs Genealogy" (p.86-168) [2/2], 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Long length manuscript "The Riggs Family of Maryland-Genealogy" (title page-page 61) [1/2], 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Long length manuscript "The Riggs Family of Maryland-Genealogy" (p.62-168) [2/2], 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Photocopies of photographs for "The Riggs Family of Maryland", 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Printed manuscript of "The Riggs Family of Maryland" (title page-p.198), 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Printed manuscript of "The Riggs Family of Maryland" (p.199-357), 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Printed manuscript of "The Riggs Family of Maryland" (p.358-525) including copies of family portraits, 1939; Series 3 Subseries 5; 2.5 Linear Feet (Box 29, Folder 4)